In this video, we're going to talk about
segments when posting transactions in
Dynamics SL and compare that to the
experience in Dynamics 365 Business
Central.
Where we will define default dimensions
on entries like vendors and customers to
create similar postings and how those
same transactions look on reports in
Dynamics 365 Business Central.
To begin, let's go to Dynamics SL and
post an invoice we received from a
vendor for some recent supplies we
bought.
In accounts payable voucher and
adjustment entry, select a vendor and
enter the vendor invoice number and
amount. Finish entering the rest of the
batch information and then release the
batch.
Once a batch is released, we'll look at
the resulting batch control report.
On the batch control report, we can see
the debit and credit posting accounts
along with the designated sub account
segments each entry will be posted to
for reporting.
Now, let's look at Dynamics 365 Business
Central and how we can set up default
dimensions on a vendor and how those are
used on transactions and reports.
If you remember from the segment and
dimension setup video, the segments we
defined in SL will migrate to Business
Central as dimensions, allowing us to
continue to slice and categorize our
transactions when posting to the main
account.
I'll first go to my vendor in Business
Central that was migrated from SL using
the cloud migration tool.
I want to assign the reporting unit and
company segment as a default dimensions.
If I wanted to lock the posting down
further, I could set the value posting
to code mandatory, which would indicate
that a dimension value must exist on a
transaction for the vendor.
However, I don't want the system to be
that rigid. We just want the dimension
value to default on transactions for us.
Next, let's enter in a purchase invoice
for this vendor, similar to how we did
it in SL,
and look at how that dimension value
will default into the transaction.
I'll go ahead and select the purchase
journal and enter in my vendor invoice
number again.
Select the vendor, key in the purchase
amount and account.
You can see in the fact box area the
dimension value has automatically
defaulted onto the transaction for me.
Before posting any journal in Business
Central, I can preview the posting to
ensure that the correct accounts are
being posted to, similar to clicking the
distributions button in Dynamics SL.
When looking at the posting preview for
this batch, I can see that it's posting
to the correct GL account and
dimensions.
Since that all looks correct, I'll go
ahead and post the invoice.
Now, let's look at the trial balance
dimension report in Business Central.
In my report option window, I've
selected to print the reporting unit
dimension.
We'll filter the report further by my GL
account number, date, reporting unit,
and company segment.
The trial balance report in Business
Central allows me to see amounts being
posted to my main accounts, similar to
Dynamics SL, as well as allowing me to
analyze transactions by various
categories.
In this example, by reporting unit and
company segment.
And that's a quick look at segments and
dimensions posting in SL and Business
Central.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.